Omid Rajabi

Canadian citizen residing in Newmarket, Ontario. (open to remote/relocation) Software engineer specializing in web development with strong fundamentals in Javascript frameworks. Passionate about programming languages, compilers, distributed systems and scalability.

🤳 (647) 778-1740 💌 contact@omidjan.ca 🔲 omidjan.ca 🛗 /omidjan 🕥 /omid-web

Skills

Languages: Javascript, Typescript, C#, Python, Java, PHP, SQL, HTML5, CSS3

Technologies: Amazon Web Services, Firebase, Heroku, Node.js(npm/yarn), .Net(NuGet), Docker(Hub), Linux

Developer Tools: Visual Studio Code, Jetbrains Rider, Visual Studio 2022, Android Studio, Postman, Gitlab, Jira, Figma, MySQL Workbench, Oracle SQL Developer, MongoDb Compass/Atlas

Frameworks: Vue/Vuex, React/Redux, React Native, Angular, Express.js, ASP.NET Core, Storybook,

Tailwind/Sass/Bootstrap, Jest/Cypress, jQuery

Methodologies: Object-oriented design (OOD), Design patterns, Test-driven development (TDD), Model-view-controller

Experience

Xe.com 11/2021 - Present

Software Developer - hybrid

Newmarket, ON

- Individual contributor in a team of 10 using Agile; building responsive, mobile-first, cross-browser compatible, and scalable web apps. Daily stand-ups. Peer reviewing PRs.
- Launched a corporate sign-up flow, increasing corporate customer sign-up completions by 50%.
- Delivered a corporate dashboard MVP that automated user KYC, saving days waiting for account approval.
- Worked with payments/identity APIs, microservices, CI/CD pipelines, and implemented unit/integration testing.
- · Provided mentorship to interns with pair programming. Showed initiative in documentation, code refactoring, and better tooling suggestion.

Q2 Management Inc.

16 months. 07/2020 - 10/2021

Full Stack Developer - remote

Newmarket, ON

- Main Contributor in a team of 4 using Scrum; designed and implemented large features across the entire stack on projects of different tech stacks. Implementing RESTful APIs.
- Launched a modern secure dashboard site, built using Material UI(MUI) library, for internal users and corporate customers, as the existing Flash site was obsolete.
- · Normalized and denormalized tables to save space and speed up queries leading to an improved dashboard page load time of up to 70%.
- Automated the covid reports, employee time sheets, customer billing, and emailing of reports to stakeholders.
- Led refactoring initiatives and guided major decisions surrounding the technical stack to implement best practices.

University of Toronto, Woodsworth College

Website Manager

5 months. 10/2019 - 02/2020 Toronto, ON

University of Toronto, OISE

4 months. Summer 2018

IT Help Desk

Toronto, ON

Bell Technical Solutions

4 months. Summer 2017

Fiber Optic Technician

Scarborough, ON

Education

University of Toronto, St. George

06/2020

Graduated with a B.S. in Computer Science & Statistics

Toronto, ON

Projects

Afghan Linkedin, afghan-linkedin.com — An interactive Vue/Pinia site where users can make profiles and posts.

Cryptoverse, cryptoapp.omidjan.ca — A site that displays live crypto prices and news using 3rd party APIs.

Local Library, express-library-omid.herokuapp.com — An interactive MVC site that simulates a library.

Programming Language Interpreter — School projects using functional programming languages Racket and Haskell.

Language Learner App, Weather App, github.com/omid-web/android-projects — Repo of past small Android projects.